

Guillaume Neirinckx

Java Developer

Date of Birth: 30/10/1997 Years of IT experience: 2 years

Nationality: Belgian
Sex: M

Introduction

After a professional experience of almost 2 years as a Java developer, Guillaume is looking for a new challenge in this domain to expand even further his knowledge.

He is eager to put into play his desire to discover new technologies.

In addition to his technical skills in development and testing, his passion and analytical mind can make him a real asset.

With his calm and sociable character, always looking for solutions, he can easily fit into any team.

Skills and competences

Computer skills and competences

Talen Java (8), Python, Erlang, Bash, C, TypeScript, Prolog, Scala, Oz, CSS, HTML

Databanken SQL, DB2, MongoDB, SQLite **Framework** Java EE (7), Angular, Flask

Versiebeheer Git (Lab & Hub)
Besturingssysteem Linux & Windows

Tools IntelliJ, PyCharm, DBeaver, VisualVM, Docker, Jenkins, Maven, REST, SOAP, WSL2, Junit, Jbehave,

ANTLR, FileZilla, Android Studio, JIRA, Confluence, Trello, Slack

Methodologie Agile, SCRUM, Kanban

<u>Language</u>		Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	Writing
FRENCH	Mother tongue	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent
DUTCH	Secundary school	Excellent	Excellent	Very good	Very good	Excellent
ENGLISH		Very	Very good	Very good	Very good	Good
GERMAN		Good	Good	Ok	Poor	Poor

Education

2015 – 2020 Bachelor + Master Computer Science – UCLouvain (Louvain-la-Neuve)

<u>Other</u>

2019 OpenWeek (UCLouvain)

2019 Data science hackathon (NRB group)





Professional experience

	Java deve	elopment	
Dates Nove	mber 2020 – September 2022	Status Finished	Customer FPS Finance
Main activities and responsibilities	project. Thanks to this prefilled each year. Goal: Adding new feat and efficient. Responsible for the inte	project, millions of tax tures, keeping the ap egration tests 7, Java 8, Maven, Do	roposed Simplified Return returns are automatically plication up to date, bug free cker, Bash, Jbehave, Jenkins,

Java development				
Dates May	Dates May 2021 – September 2022 Status Finished Customer FPS Finance			
Main activities and responsibilities	to automatically deter or non-resident, single • Goal: Adding new fea (integration tests) and	mine whether one is ta: or couple). tures, keeping the appl efficient (profiling tools, 7, Java 8, Maven, Docl	developers. Its primary role is xable and how (as a resident lication up to date, bug free indexes). ker, Bash, Jbehave, Jenkins,	

Master Thesis

	Erlang c	development - IoT	
Year 2019 -	2020	Mentor Prof. Peter Van Roy	
Details	by doing it on thMotivation: Expondes cannot keep	Goal: Prove that Edge Computing can be done even closer to the edge by doing it on the IoT devices themselves. Motivation: Exponential growth of these devices, cloud and intermediary nodes cannot keep up with the pace. Approach: Show that this approach is feasible by implementing a relevant	
	Application: An i equipped IoT de	indoor person tracking system comprised of sonar evices that share sonar measures with each other to ar) real time the position of persons (1-2) in a room. lang, Bash	

University projects

		Python dev	velopment
Yea	r 2018-2019		Customer UCLouvain
Details	•	Goal: Design in a team	of 6 developers a web application capable of
		posting the same messe Twitter, Slack,).	age on lots of different social networks (Facebook,
	•		
	•	Approach: Agile	
	•	Technologies: Python, F	Flask, REST. SQLAIchemy

Android (Java) development





Year 2017-2	018
Details	 Goal: Design in a team of 4 developers a cool game for Android where one can simulate investments on cryptocurrency with real time data, play the wheel of fortune, buy items (e.g. a house) with earned money on an interactive map etc.
	Approach: AgileTechnologies: Android Studio, Java, LibGDX, SQLite

	Android (Java) development			
Year 2016-2				
Details	Goal: Design in a team of 4 developers an app where people can learn how to cook excellent recipes.			
	Approach: AgileTechnologies: Android Studio, Java, Xml, SQLite			

Web development – MEAN app				
Year 2016-2	Year 2016-2017			
Details	•	to buy cars from an imagi	o with secure login features where the user is able inary car seller. Express.js, Angular, Node.js	

Personal projects

Python development - Artificial Intelligence			
Year 2021			
Details	 Goal: Design a bot that can competitively play chess on its own and kick some butt of other chess players/bots. Motivation: To improve my Python skills while having fun. Technologies: Python ELO rating of this bot on Lichess.org: > 1800 		